<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour of Leesburg</string>

    <string name="category_history">Town History</string>
    <string name="category_sites">Historical Town Sites</string>

    <string name ="early_settlement">Following the 1722 Treaty of Albany, in which the Iroquois
        abandoned all lands east of the Blue Ridge Mountains to the colony of Virginia, colonists
        and new immigrants of a wide variety of ethnic and religious backgrounds began settling the
        lands that would become Loudoun County. In 1730, Thomas, the 6th Earl of Fairfax,
        granted 4054 acres, including what would become Leesburg, to Francis Awbrey.
        At the intersection of the major north-south Carolina Road (now U.S. Highway 15) and
        the east-west oriented Potomac Ridge Road (now Virginia Highway 7), a small settlement
        emerged. </string>

    <string name="founding_and_revolution">In 1757, the Assembly of Virginia selected this
        settlement for the location of the Loudoun County courthouse. The town\'s name was changed
        to Leesburg, for the Lee family, by an Act of Assembly in September 1758 that officially
        established the town. Initial town trustees included Nicholas Minor, Philip Ludwell Lee,
        and Francis Lightfoot Lee, who were responsible for regulating building in the town.
        The land was owned by Nicholas Minor, who had hired John Hough to survey and plat his 60 acres
        into 70 lots to form a town, which he called George Town. The original map from 1757 is
        no longer in existence; his 1759 revised map shows Leesburg\'s subdivision into 70 lots
        divided by three north-south and four east-west streets.
        At first, Minor sold lots for a mere £3, but soon increased his price to £10. In order to prevent
        the shoddy construction he was seeing, Minor also required purchasers to build on the lots,
        giving most three years to build a brick, stone or wood house twenty feet wide and sixteen
        feet long. If they failed to build in a timely fashion, the property reverted back to Minor.
        Leesburg was a commercial crossroads for Shenandoah Valley farmers near Winchester seeking to move
        their goods to merchants in Alexandria and Georgetown. With the opening of the Leesburg
        Turnpike (Virginia Highway 7) - in 1820, the relationship was strengthened.
        At the start of the American Revolution, Leesburg had fewer than 500 residents. Due in part to its
        ethnic and religious diversity, which included English, German, and Scotch-Irish belonging
        to Anglican, Baptist, Methodist, and Quaker (Society of Friends) congregations, many
        Leesburg residents supported the American Revolution.
        In June 1774, Leesburg and Loudoun freeholders, meeting in Leesburg, passed the Loudoun County
        Resolves, which sent a delegation to a Virginia-wide meeting to consider responses to
        British taxation and other provocations. Loudoun County's militia, in which every freeman
        between the ages of 16 and 50 was enrolled, was the largest in Virginia with 1,746 men.</string>

</resources>
