<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour of Leesburg</string>

    <string name="category_history">Town History</string>
    <string name="category_sites">Historical Town Sites</string>

    <string name="early_settlement_title">Early Settlement and Founding</string>
    <string name="founding_title">Founding and Revolution</string>
    <string name="war_title">War of 1812 and Lafayette\'s Visit</string>
    <string name="leesburg_inc_title">Leesburg Inc.</string>

    <string name="balls_bluff_title">Balls Bluff Battlefield and National Cemetery</string>
    <string name="marshall_house_title">The Marshall House</string>
    <string name="oatlands_plantation_title">Oatlands Plantation</string>
    <string name="paxton_manor_title">Paxton Manor</string>
    <string name="morven_park_title">Morven Park</string>

    <string name="early_settlement_info">Following the 1722 Treaty of Albany, in which the Iroquois
        abandoned all lands east of the Blue Ridge Mountains to the colony of Virginia, colonists
        and new immigrants of a wide variety of ethnic and religious backgrounds began settling the
        lands that would become Loudoun County. In 1730, Thomas, the 6th Earl of Fairfax,
        granted 4054 acres, including what would become Leesburg, to Francis Awbrey.
        At the intersection of the major north-south Carolina Road (now U.S. Highway 15) and
        the east-west oriented Potomac Ridge Road (now Virginia Highway 7), a small settlement
        emerged. </string>

    <string name="founding_and_revolution_info">In 1757, the Assembly of Virginia selected this
        settlement for the location of the Loudoun County courthouse. The town\'s name was changed
        to Leesburg, for the Lee family, by an Act of Assembly in September 1758 that officially
        established the town. Initial town trustees included Nicholas Minor, Philip Ludwell Lee,
        and Francis Lightfoot Lee, who were responsible for regulating building in the town.
        The land was owned by Nicholas Minor, who had hired John Hough to survey and plat his 60 acres
        into 70 lots to form a town, which he called George Town. The original map from 1757 is
        no longer in existence; his 1759 revised map shows Leesburg\'s subdivision into 70 lots
        divided by three north-south and four east-west streets.

        "\n\n"At first, Minor sold lots for a mere £3, but soon increased his price to £10. In order to prevent
        the shoddy construction he was seeing, Minor also required purchasers to build on the lots,
        giving most three years to build a brick, stone or wood house twenty feet wide and sixteen
        feet long. If they failed to build in a timely fashion, the property reverted back to Minor.
        Leesburg was a commercial crossroads for Shenandoah Valley farmers near Winchester seeking to move
        their goods to merchants in Alexandria and Georgetown. With the opening of the Leesburg
        Turnpike (Virginia Highway 7) - in 1820, the relationship was strengthened.
        At the start of the American Revolution, Leesburg had fewer than 500 residents. Due in part to its
        ethnic and religious diversity, which included English, German, and Scotch-Irish belonging
        to Anglican, Baptist, Methodist, and Quaker (Society of Friends) congregations, many
        Leesburg residents supported the American Revolution.
        In June 1774, Leesburg and Loudoun freeholders, meeting in Leesburg, passed the Loudoun County
        Resolves, which sent a delegation to a Virginia-wide meeting to consider responses to
        British taxation and other provocations. Loudoun County\'s militia, in which every freeman
        between the ages of 16 and 50 was enrolled, was the largest in Virginia with 1,746 men.
    </string>

    <string name="war_of_1812">During the War of 1812, Leesburg served as the temporary national
        archives of the United States. Faced with British invasion of Washington, D.C., the
        Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, congressional journals, George Washington\'s
        correspondence and other official documents were squirreled away in a vacant Leesburg
        house, with former county sheriff and Methodist pastor John Littlejohn keeping the keys.
        A decade later, President James Monroe resided just south of town at Oak Hill,
        where he wrote the Monroe Doctrine in 1823. In 1825, the Marquis de la Fayette,
        a personal friend of Monroe, was feted in Leesburg during his farewell
        tour of the United States. Lafayette had served during the American Revolution under
        George Washington, and was wounded at the Battle of Brandywine. During his 1824-1825 tour
        of America, he visited all twenty-four of the United States.
    </string>

    <string name="leesburg_inc">The Act of Incorporation of the Town of Leesburg by the General
        Assembly was signed 18 February 1813, providing for elected officials to pass laws
        governing the town and manage town affairs. Acts and ordinances governing a variety of
        activities in the town quickly followed.

        "\n\n"One act, passed 14 August 1813, held residents of lots fronting on King and Loudoun Streets
        responsible for paving the footways and providing gutters along the street, using stone or
        bricks that met the guidelines of the town\'s plan. If owners failed to comply in a timely
        fashion, the Street Commission was authorized to do the paving and bill the homeowners.
    </string>

    <string name="balls_bluff_info">The site of one of the largest Civil War engagements in
        Loudoun County. It is a battlefield area and a United States National Cemetery, located 2
        miles (3.2 km) northeast of Leesburg, Virginia. The cemetery is the third smallest national
        cemetery in the United States. Fifty-four Union Army dead from the Battle of Ball\'s Bluff
        are interred in 25 graves in the half-acre plot; the identity of all of the interred except
        for one, James Allen of the 15th Massachusetts, are unknown. Monuments to fallen Confederate
        Sergeant Clinton Hatcher and Union brigade commander Edward Dickinson Baker are located
        next to the cemetery, though neither is buried there. While the stone wall-enclosed
        cemetery itself is managed through the Culpeper National Cemetery and owned by the
        Department of Veterans Affairs, the balance of the 223-acre (0.90 km2) park is managed
        through the Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority.
    </string>

    <string name="marshall_house_info">
        The Marshall House (formerly Dodona Manor), is situated on 3.8 acres of gardens on
        the eastern end of Leesburg\'s Old and Historic District. The site is designated a National
        Historic Landmark as the residence of General George C. Marshall from 1941 until 1959.
        During his residency in the home, General Marshall served our nation as Chief of Staff of
        the Army, as Special Envoy to China, as Secretary of State, as President of the American
        Red Cross, and as Secretary of Defense. His career as a military officer spanned 44 years,
        including distinguished service in two world wars. General Marshall was the architect of
        the European Recovery Plan (The Marshall Plan), and was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in
        1953. General Marshall was described as the "Greatest American of the twentieth century"
        by both Franklin Roosevelt and Winston Churchill. More than 90 percent of the items in the
        house belonged to the Marshalls when they lived here in the 1950s.
    </string>

    <string name="oatlands_plantation_info">The Oatlands property is composed of the main mansion
        and 415 acres (168.0 ha) of farmland and gardens. The house is judged one of the finest
        Federal period country estate houses in the nation. Oatlands Plantation was established by
        George Carter, a great grandson of Robert "King" Carter, in 1798 on 3,408 acres (1,980 ha)
        of farmland. It started as a wheat farm, but expanded to include other grains, sheep, a
        gristmill and a saw mill, and a vineyard. In 1804, Carter began construction of a Federal
        mansion, which he expanded in the 1820s and 1830s. He also built a terraced garden and
        numerous outbuildings.

        "\n\n"The success of Carter\'s plantation and business ventures depended on slave labor.
        Seventeen enslaved people worked the property when Carter began farming. By purchase and
        natural increase, the number of slaves had risen to 133 at the time of the 1860 census.
        Their work included planting and harvesting the fields; caring for farm animals; domestic
        employment such as cooking, cleaning, caring for children, and sewing; and probably trades
        such as blacksmithing and milling.
    </string>

    <string name="paxton_manor_info">Paxton Manor, first known as Carlheim Manor, was conceived by
        a wealthy industrialist from Pennsylvania, named Charles R. Paxton. In 1869, Paxton moved
        into Leesburg with his wife, Rachel, and purchased 765 acres of land. His property\’s
        massive extent afforded a home of extreme size as well, and so in 1872, it was certainly a
        lavish structure which architect Henry C. Dudley delivered4. Dudley\’s interlaced dark brown
        sandstone with pinkish ones to create a two and a half story main house that mimicked the
        look of Italian villas. His approach to exterior details was restrained and simple, but he
        gave the inside of the house much more attention. Dudley installed beautiful marble
        mantels, a massive central staircase, elaborate panel work… even a central heating system.
        For Rachel Paxton, this comfortable 20,000 square foot home was the ideal setting to host
        lavish parties and raise her only child, Margaret.

        "\n\n"The house is built on an area which has experienced plenty of supernatural activity and
        warfare. Leesburg\’s earliest occupants include the Algonquian Indians, who believed in the
        afterlife and practiced shamanic rituals. Perhaps their efforts to reconnect with the
        deceased are what have left portals to the hereafter still open. Two other tribes, the
        Catawba and the Lenape, frequently butted heads, and had a particularly bloody battle right
        by Leesburg. You can imagine that the spirits of these warring warriors have been unhappily
        disturbed by the influx of present day tourists.

        "\n\n"Leesburg\’s colonial era is also marked by much black magic and bloodshed. Though Virginia
        was not as eager as Massachusetts to prosecute those accused of witchcraft, it too had its
        fair share of trials. You can be sure that the spirits of the wrongly convicted have yet
        to move on from the area. Ghosts of dead soldiers are also believed to be a chief source
        of Leesburg\’s paranormal activity. In fact, the famous Civil War Battle, the Battle of
        Ball\'s Bluff, occurred right by the Carlheim estate. It is said that the Paxton house is
        haunted by traumatized troops who may have sought refuge at the building.
    </string>

    <string name="morven_park_info">Morven Park first opened to the public in 1967, under the
        operation of the Westmoreland Davis Memorial Foundation. Marguerite Davis, who with her
        husband Westmoreland, governor of Virginia during World War I, purchased the property in
        1903, established the Foundation in order to preserve their home and its stunning grounds
        for the benefit of the public. Marguerite owned the estate until her death in 1963.

        "\n\n"Morven Park\'s iconic mansion began as a small fieldstone house, built circa 1780 and
        expanded upon through the decades until it became the 22-room Greek revival mansion we
        see today. For 100 years, Morven Park was the home of the Swann family, beginning in 1800
        with Thomas Swann Sr., who served as Attorney General for Washington, D.C.. Before his
        death, Swann distributed and sold portions of Morven Park to his children, and in 1842,
        Thomas Swann Jr. purchased his siblings’ properties to become sole owner of Morven Park.
        Mr. Swann, Jr., made his primary residence in Maryland, keeping Morven Park as his summer
        retreat. A successful railroad executive, he moved into politics and served as mayor of
        Baltimore, governor of Maryland and in the U.S. House of Representatives for five terms.
        Mar Mercer Swann Carter, Thomas Swann, Jr.\'s daughter, inherited Morven Park and she
        remained its owner until 1898. By the time Westmoreland Davis purchased the estate in 1903,
        it had changed hands several times, and they became its final private owners.
    </string>




</resources>
